Adam Tsuchiyama

Data Analyst

CONTACT INFO

Email: adamtsuch21@gmail.com

Phone: 269-986-7161

GitHub: github.com/adamtsuch21

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/adam-tsuchiyama/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cook

2016 - present

Provided dining and catering services for Trevecca Nazarene University and Belmont University.

Chartwells at Trevecca, 2019 - Present

- Cooked and prepared food for students and staff (Approx. 400-600 people).
- Determined what products should be ordered for inventory.
- Planned menu weekly based off of feedback from students and inventory.

Sodexo at Belmont, 2016 - 2019

- Cooked and prepared food for students and staff (Approx. 800-1000 people).
- Determined what products should be ordered for inventory.

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Data Analytics Boot Camp, 2020

Belmont University

B.S, Audio Engineering, 2015-2017

- Recording and Mixing Engineer for a cover of the "Friends" and "That 70's Show" Theme songs.
- Recording and Mixing Engineer a cover of "Pump It Up" by Elvis Costello.
- Front of House Engineer for the 2016 Belmont "Urban/Pop" Showcase.
- Systems Engineer for the 2017 Belmont "Best of the Best" Showcase.

PROFILE SUMMARY

Whether it's determining how to incorporate the current inventory into a menu, or planning a menu based off student feedback, I've always enjoyed using critical thinking and analysis to solve problems. Through my experience at Nashville Software School, I've learned how to apply those same critical thinking skills to data analytics.

DATA ANALYSIS EXPERIENCE

Data Analytics Boot Camp

Nashville Software School, 2020

Nashville Software School is a non-profit vocational school specializing in education of web development, data analysis, and data science.

Six month part-time program serving as an introduction into data analytics. Emphasis on analytical thinking and analytics workflow through hands on training.

Tools Learned: SQL, Excel, Tableau, Power BI, GitHub

Nashville Software School Projects

App Store Project

- Worked in a team of 4 to determine the most profitable mobile applications, using data from both the Apple App Store and the Google Play Store.
- Recommended a top 10 list of apps which should be purchased based off of profitability.
- o Tool Used: SQL

Billboard Hot 100 Project

- Determined similarities between pop hits on the Billboard Hot 100 charts, using Billboard Hot 100 chart data and Spotify data.
 Focused on similarities in genre, tempo, energy, and loudness.
- Found R&B was the most popular genre throughout the chart's history, but Hip Hop had been the most popular genre since the 2000s. Also, uptempo, energetic, and loud songs were popular on the chart.
- Created a dashboard to report my findings.
- o Tools Used: Excel, Power BI

The General - Hurricane Project

- Worked in a team of 4 to determine which zip codes were most affected by hurricanes, using data provided by *The General* on car insurance claims.
- Found that zip codes in Florida and Texas had the most claims and the highest cost of damages. Also, we found that hurricanes having been getting stronger over time.
- Created a storyboard in Tableau to report our findings.
- o Tools Used: Python, Tableau

Final Capstone Project - Spotify Remasters

- Determined whether remastered versions of songs changed the "character" of the original master, using data from the Spotify Web API.
- Found that there were significant differences between the master and the remaster in terms of timbre. Also, songs from the 1980s and Electronic, R&B, and Hip Hop songs showed the biggest differences.
- Created a storyboard in Tableau to report my findings.
- o Tools Used: Python, Tableau